{
  "version": 2.0,
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "The function of __________ is to isolate the part of the power system in case of abnormal conditions.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Circuit Breaker",
        "b": "Isolator",
        "c": "Insulator",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Characteristic of high voltage rating Circuit Breaker :-",
      "answers": {
        "a": "High reliability electrically and mutually",
        "b": "Capability of interrupting capacitive and inductive circuits and fault currents of all values within their rating",
        "c": "Slower time response",
        "d": "Both High reliability electrically and mutually and Capability of interrupting capacitive and inductive circuits and fault currents of all values within their rating"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In oil circuit breaker (O.C.B) the range exists between",
      "answers": {
        "a": "75MVA at 2.5 kV and 50000MVA at 250kV",
        "b": "7.5MVA at 2.5 kV and 50000MVA at 250kV",
        "c": "250MVA at 2.5 kV and 5000MVA at 250kV",
        "d": "25MVA at 2.5 kV and 5000MVA at 250kV"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Advantages of using Air blast Circuit breakers :",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Current chopping",
        "b": "Sensitivity to restricting voltage",
        "c": "Short arc duration",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "Sulphur hexafluoride (SF6)",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Is an inert gas",
        "b": "Has high dielectric strength",
        "c": "Heat transfer property is about 16 times that of air because of high density",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "In SF6 Circuit breaker ________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "No risk of fire",
        "b": "No reduction of dielectric strength",
        "c": "Current chopping tendency is minimized",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The voltage across the contacts during the arcing period is known as ______",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Recovery voltage",
        "b": "Restriking voltage",
        "c": "Arc voltage",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The transient voltage appearing across the contacts during arc period is called ________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Recovery voltage",
        "b": "Restriking voltage",
        "c": "Arc voltage",
        "d": "All"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "When low inductive current is interrupted by a Circuit breaker and the arc generating force of the Circuit breaker and is more than necessary to interrupt a low magnitude of current, the current will be interrupted before its natural zero instant. It is termed as ________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Restriking",
        "b": "Recovery instant",
        "c": "Current chopping",
        "d": "Arcing voltage"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "_______ is the r.m.s value of current which the Circuit breaker is capable of carrying continuously at its rated frequency under specified condition.",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Breaking capacity",
        "b": "Making capacity",
        "c": "Short-time capacity",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "d",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "The peak value of current (including the DC component) during first cycle of current wave after the closure of Circuit breaker is known as __________",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Breaking capacity",
        "b": "Making capacity",
        "c": "Short-time capacity",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "b",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "_________ is the current (r.m.s value) that a Circuit breaker is capable of breaking under specified conditions and given recovery voltage",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Breaking capacity",
        "b": "Making capacity",
        "c": "Short-time capacity",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "a",
      "difficulty": ""
    },
    {
      "question": "__________ of a Circuit breaker depends upon its ability to withstand the temperature rise and the electromagnetic force effects",
      "answers": {
        "a": "Breaking capacity",
        "b": "Making capacity",
        "c": "Short-time capacity",
        "d": "None"
      },
      "explanations": {
        "a": "",
        "b": "",
        "c": "",
        "d": ""
      },
      "correctAnswer": "c",
      "difficulty": ""
    }
  ]
}
